Guide to R. Buckminster Fuller. Inventions; twelve around one M1592
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
R. Buckminster Fuller. Inventions; twelve around one: portfolio of thirteen screenprints and text
1981
M1592
Dept. of Special Collections & University Archives
3.5 Linear feet (1 large portfolio; no. XII of XX, containing 13 signed prints)
Each of the thirteen prints consists of two 30" x 40" screenprinted sheets, one of which illustrates drawings for a patent invention by Fuller, and the second sheet illustrates the realization of the concept.
Patent invention drawings screenprinted in white ink on clear polyester film overlaid on blue backing sheet to create the effect of a blueprint. Photo realization of invention screenprinted on Lenox 100 percent rag paper. Screenprinted polyester film sheet as an overlay screenprinted photo realization sheet. The text pages and blue backing are Curtis Tweedweave 100% rag paper made especially for the Fuller portfolio series.
Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-1983
Access to Collection
Copy 1 is open for research use. Copy 2 is closed for use except with express permission of the Head of Special Collections.
Acquisition Information
Copy 1 was given by Allegra Fuller to Stanford University, Special Collections in 2007; copy 2 was purchased in 2014.
Historical note
Boxed limited series of inventions by Buckminster Fuller, collection of forty four individual unbound pages represent thirteen inventions of Fuller, produced under direction of Fuller by Colophon, Cincinnati, Ohio by Solway Gallery. The thirteen inventions are presented with two prints, one which illustrates drawing for a patent invention, the second illustrates the realization of the concept. The two screen prints may be presented separately in two frames or together as an overlay. Dimensions: 30” x 40”. Each of the thirteen prints is hand signed by Buckminster Fuller on the clear film element. Many the signed series was witnessed by his architectural partner Thomas T. K. Zung, adjuvant (Fuller’s term).
Carl Solway Gallery.; Architecture--United States--History--20th century; Engineering design.; Screen prints; Technology--Social aspects.
- 1928 – 4D House (Flat-box 1, Item 1)
- 1933 – Dymaxion Car (Flat-box 1, Item 2)
- 1938 – Dymaxion Bathroom (Flat-box 1, Item 3)
- 1941 – Dymaxion Deployment Unit (DDU) (Flat-box 1, Item 4)
- 1946 – Dymaxion Dwelling Machine (Flat-box 1, Item 5)
- 1954 – Geodesic Dome (Flat-box 1, Item 6)
- 1956 – Octetruss (Flat-box 1, Item 7)
- 1959 – Tensegrity (Flat-box 1, Item 8)
- 1959 – Submarisle (Flat-box 1, Item 9)
- 1961 – Monohex Geodesic Dome (Flat-box 1, Item 10)
- 1960 – Laminar Geodesic Dome (Flat-box 1, Item 11)
- 1968 – Rowing Needles (Flat-box 1, Item 12)
- 1973 – Non-Symmetrical Tension-Integrity Structures (Flat-box 1, Item 13)